Michael McCosh

Mont Vernon, NH 03057

Phone: (603) 858-4958 | Email: michael.mccosh@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaelmccosh/ Web Development Portfolio: https://michaelmccosh.com/

Summary

Software Engineer with management experience, understands that positive user experiences are only achieved through meticulous attention to detail and skillful project management. Delivering above expectation is the driving motivation for unique medical, commercial, or residential projects.

Technical Skills

Troubleshooting, Networking, AutoCAD, SIMPL/SIMPL+, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, nodeJS, React, Python.

Work Experience

2008 to 2019 - Image Stream Medical / Olympus | Littleton, MA Senior System Programmer / VTC Engineer / System designer

- A/V Control systems for world class medical training facilities that served as showpieces for attracting customers and showcasing company technology.
- Developed core product API that enabled increased customer versatility allowing use in expanded markets.
- Created Protocol Translator when audio device went "end of life", saving untold hours for development team because they did not need to develop new device driver for older product.

2006 to 2008 - Smith & Nephew Endoscopy | Andover, MA Senior Development Engineer

- Key member of a small team that made a giant impact in the field of audio video integration in hospital operating rooms.
- Managed 2 programming teams with different styles and functions to deploy product (systems) for a new, emerging market, which also expanded sales for existing products.
- The "Digital Operating Room" systems were built with Crestron hardware and the quantity of systems installed resulted in becoming the largest volume Crestron dealer at the time.

2003 to 2006 - Crimson Tech / Univisions Crimson Group | Wilmington, MA Senior Systems Programmer / Programming Dept Manager

- Managed a team of programmers that deployed hundreds of systems, each custom tailored to the unique needs of the user community.
- Developed track record of accurately estimating time and resources needed for programming projects resulting in "on time, on budget" project programming completion.
- Standardized UI layouts resulting in quicker completion of touch panel programming projects.

1998 to 2003 - McCosh Consulting | Manchester, NH Proprietor / Consultant / Programmer

- System design consulting.
- Crestron and AMX programming, User Interface ergonomics.
- Remote access via IP communication.
- Significant customer base in residential and commercial markets.

1977 to 1998 included a wide range of experience including business owner, manager, sales, installation, customer support, engineering, quality, training, manufacturing, repair, computer networks, home automation, and professional photography.

Education

UNH Coding boot camp for full stack web development. An intense 24 week boot camp covering an array of web programming languages for front end and back end applications. Graduated Dec, 2020.

Specialties *I* certifications:

- Silver Certified Crestron Master Programmer
- Certificate of Achievement awards in various career fields